# János Kócs

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

janos.kocs@outlook.com

<u>linkedin.com/in/janoskocs</u> github.com/janoskocs

#### **PORTFOLIO**

https://janoskocs.com

#### **PROFILE**

When I was a kid, my computer ran Windows 98, and it was the coolest thing ever. This passion for computers has been reignited last year when I enrolled in a software engineering boot camp.

After the course, I took on the role of a TA for two cohorts. This experience allowed me to mentor and teach people how to code.

I'm driven by that "wow, you built that?" and the belief that I can make a real impact with software.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, React, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Git

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BrainStation | Diploma**

#### **Software Engineering**

JAN 2023 - APR 2023 LONDON, UK

#### **BrainStation | Certificate**

#### Cybersecurity

JAN 2024 - MAR 2024 LONDON, UK

#### Anglia Ruskin University |

# BSc (Hons) Business and Marketing

JAN 2019 - DEC 2021 LONDON, UK

#### **INTERESTS**









#### **PROJECTS**

# Portfolio site | Live | Repository

JAN 2024

- Frontend stack: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, React.
- Containerised React app utilising Docker and Nginx image.
- Implemented CI/CD pipeline through GitHub Actions.
- Configured AWS EC2 instance for deployment.

# MemoVault social media | Live | Repository

APR 2023

- Frontend stack: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, React, React Router Dom, sentiment analysis API, NPM packages.
- Backend stack: Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, JWT authentication.
- Designed and developed a social media app that focuses on mental health.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **BrainStation**

# Senior Teaching Assistant - Software Engineering

NOV 2023 - FEB 2024

- Mentored 17 students through 1:1 sessions, discussing individual blockers.
- Led 60 open studio sessions, guiding, and addressing code-related queries from an average of 7 students per session.
- Conducted 20 challenge workshops, presenting code problems to students.

# **Teaching Assistant - Software Engineering**

JUN 2023 - SEPT 2024

- Graded 130 student projects, delivering feedback on areas for improvement.
- Conducted code reviews for 13 students, providing feedback on best practices.
- Coordinated weekly lecture reviews, including quizzes, and provided explanations on technical topics.

# **GXO Logistics UK**

# **Systems Administrator**

FEB 2023 - DEC 2024

- Automated 10 operational reports using Tableau and Oracle SQL to save costs.
- Developed a React QR code generator app, saving colleagues 20 minutes daily.
- Supported operational team by troubleshooting issues using a ticket system.

# Warehouse Ops Trainer II

JAN 2022 - JAN 2023

- Developed an interactive app to deliver fire safety trainings to management which helped reduce emergency evacuation time to 2 minutes.
- Delivered health and safety trainings to over 700 colleagues, resulting in a 15% drop in accidents within a year.
- Modernised training records to identify refresher requirements which lead to a 21% increase in compliance.